■
翻譯  艾瑞卡  ellaxinxin
翻譯  想吃鍋巴  萊吉
翻譯  牛奶器
校對  臉盆王子  somehacker
后期  8T     總監  somehacker
@懶死放映室 團隊譯制
舊京山港口
起來  站起來啊
Get up! Get up!
獲勝者是
The winner,
將對手完全壓制住的
by total annihilation,
山哥
Yama!
下一個是誰
Who is next?
誰有種進來挑戰小山哥
Who has the guts to step into the ring with little Yama?
山哥
Yama!
我能試試嗎
Can I try?
我有個機器人  自己做的
I have a robot. I built it myself.
來吧  小子
Beat it, kid.
本店規矩  先付錢后上場
House rules. You gotta pay to play.
這些夠嗎
Is this enough?
你叫什么  小家伙
What's your name, little boy?
宏  濱田宏[與英雄同音]
Hiro. Hiro Hamada.
機器人準備  零蛋君
Prepare your bot, zero.
兩個機器人上場
Two bots enter,
只有一個能離開
one bot leaves.
選手準備
Fighters ready?
開始
Fight!
剛剛是我第一次比賽  能再試一次嗎
That was my first fight. I... Can I try again?
輸不起就別玩  小家伙
No one likes a sore loser, little boy.
回去吧
Go home.
我還有錢
I've got more money.
選手準備
Fighters ready?
開始
Fight!
無敵機器人  毀滅模式
Mega-bot, destroy.
什么
What?
-小山哥沒有啦  -但是  怎么
- No more little Yama. - But, wha...
這不可能
This is not possible!
我也不敢相信
Hey, I'm as surprised as you are.
新手運氣好唄
Beginner's luck.
想再來一局嗎  山哥
Do you want to go again, Yama?
沒人能從山哥這誆錢
No one hustles Yama!
給他點教訓
Teach him a lesson.
伙計們  我們談談好嗎
Hey, fellas. Let's talk about this.
-宏  上車  -正
- Hiro! Get on! - Tadashi!
來得真是時候
Good timing!
我的媽啊
Oh, mama!
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
-你受傷了嗎  -沒有
- Are you hurt? - No.
那你是腦子進水了嗎  傻瓜
Then what were you thinking, knucklehead?
你十三歲就高中畢業
You graduated high school when you were 13,
你就成天干這個
and this is what you're doing?
他們在這
There they are!
抓緊了
Hold on!
好棒
Yes!
回來
Get back here.
機器人競技是違法的
Bot fighting is illegal.
你會害自己進監獄的
You're going to get yourself arrested.
機器人競技不違法
Bot fighting is not illegal.
拿來賭錢  那才是違法的
Betting on bot fighting, that's... that's illegal.
但收益頗豐
But so lucrative!
哥哥  我現在鴻運當頭  勢不可擋啊
I'm on a roll, big brother! And there is no stopping me!
不好
Oh, no.
警局
凱斯嬸嬸
Hi, Aunt Cass.
你們沒事吧  告訴我你們沒事
Are you guys okay? Tell me you're okay.
-我們沒事  -我們很好
- We're fine. - We're okay.
那就好
Oh, good.
那你們兩個傻瓜是腦子進水了嗎
Then what were you two knuckleheads thinking?
十年了
For 10 years,
我已經盡全力把你倆拉扯大
I have done the best I could to raise you.
我是個完美的家長嗎  不是
Have I been perfect? No.
我了解小孩嗎  不了解
Do I know anything about children? No.
我該買本如何教育子女的書嗎
Should I have picked up a book on parenting?
或許該買本了
Probably!
我想說什么來著
Where was I going with this? I had a point.
-對不起  -我們愛你  凱斯嬸嬸
- Sorry. - We love you, Aunt Cass.
我也愛你們
Well, I love you, too!
因為你倆我今天不得不提前打烊
I had to close up early because of you two felons.
在垮掉一代詩歌之夜
On beat poetry night.
化壓力為食欲  都怪你倆
Stress eating. Because of you.
來吧  摩奇
Come on, Mochi.
真的好好吃
This is really good!
你最好在凱斯嬸嬸把咖啡廳吃空之前
You better make this up to Aunt Cass
趕緊彌補過錯
before she eats everything in the cafe.
那必須
For sure.
但愿你吸取教訓了  笨蛋
And I hope you learned your lesson, bonehead.
當然了
Absolutely.
你要去機器人競技是不是
You're going bot fighting, aren't you?
就在城市另一邊  現在報名還能趕上
There's a fight across town. If I book, I can still make it.
你什么時候
When are you gonna
才能把你的腦袋瓜用在正地方
start doing something with that big brain of yours?
什么  跟你一樣去上大學嗎
What? Go to college like you?
這樣別人就能教我已經知道的東西了嗎
So people can tell me stuff I already know?
難以置信
Unbelievable.
爸爸媽媽會怎么說你
What would mom and dad say?
我不知道
I don't know.
他們已經不在了
They're gone.
我三歲他們就去世了  記得嗎
They died when I was three, remember?
-我帶你去  -真的嗎
- I'll take you. - Really?
反正我也攔不住你
I can't stop you from going,
但我也不能讓你一個人去
but I'm not going to let you go on your own.
好極了
Sweet.
舊京山理工學院
我們到你的書呆學校來干嘛
What are we doing at your nerd school?
機器人競技是在那邊
Bot-fight's that way!
伊藤石崗機器人學實驗室
得拿點東西
Gotta grab something.
要很久嗎
Is this gonna take long?
放松  別抱怨啦  馬上就好
Relax, you big baby. We'll be in and out.
再說你也沒見過我的實驗室
Anyway, you've never seen my lab.
好極了  能看到你的書呆子實驗室
Oh, great, I get to see your nerd lab!
小心
Heads up!
電磁懸浮嗎
Electro-mag suspension?
-你是誰  -我是...
- Who are you? - I'm...
速美子  這是我弟弟宏
Go go, this is my brother Hiro.
歡迎來到書呆實驗室
Welcome to the nerd lab.
是啊
Yeah.
我從來沒見過電磁懸浮用于單車上
I've never seen electro-mag suspension on a bike before.
零摩擦  單車更快
Zero resistance, faster bike.
但還不夠快
But, not fast enough,
目前來說
yet.
別動  請站到線后面去
Do not move. Behind the line, please.
山葵  這是我弟弟宏
Hey, Wasabi. This is my brother Hiro.
你好  宏  準備好大開眼界
Hello, Hiro. Prepare to be amazed.
接著
Catch.
-激光誘導等離子體  -沒錯
- Laser-induced plasma? - Oh, yeah.
只要一點磁約束就能有超高精密度
With a little magnetic confinement for ultra-precision.
這么亂怎么找東西
Wow. How do you find anything in this mess?
我有系統化擺放
I have a system.
每一件都有自己的位置
There's a place for everything,
一切都是有序的
and everything in its place.
-借我這個  -別這樣啊
- Need this! - You can't do that!
這樣就無序了  社會需要秩序啊
This is anarchy! Society has rules!
抱歉
Excuse me!
借過一下
Coming through!
正
Tadashi!
老天  你就是宏了吧
Oh, my gosh. You must be Hiro!
我聽過你很多事
I've heard so much about you!
時間剛好  時間剛好
Perfect timing. Perfect timing.
好多碳化鎢啊
That's a whole lot of tungsten carbide.
足足400磅
400 pounds of it!
過來  過來
Come here, come here, come here.
你會喜歡這個的
You're going to love this.
摻點高氯酸  一滴鈷顏料
A dash of perchloric acid, a smidge of cobalt,
一丁點過氧化氫
a hint of hydrogen peroxide,
加熱至500開氏度
super-heated to 500 Kelvin, and...
完成啦  有沒有很棒
Ta-da! It's pretty great, huh?
很粉紅
It's so pink.
最精彩的部分到了
Here's the best part.
很贊是不是
I know, right?
化學金屬脆化
Chemical metal embrittlement.
不錯啊  檸蜜
Not bad, Honey Lemon.
"檸蜜"  "速美子"  "山葵"
"Honey Lemon"? "Go go"? "Wasabi"?
我就把山葵灑在衣服上一次
I spill wasabi on my shirt one time, people.
就一次
One time!
綽號都是弗雷迪取的
Fred is the one who comes up with the nicknames.
弗雷迪是誰
Who's Fred?
就是我  在這
This guy, right here!
別害怕  只是道具服而已
Don't be alarmed. It is just a suit.
我真人不長這樣
This is not my real face and body.
在下大名弗雷迪
The name's Fred.
白天是學校吉祥物  但到了晚上
School mascot by day, but by night,
我還是學校吉祥物
I am also a school mascot.
你什么專業的
So, what's your major?
不  不  我不是學生
No, no, no, I'm not a student.
但我是個狂熱科學愛好者
But I am a major science enthusiast.
我想讓小蜜給我研制個分子式
I've been trying to get Honey to develop a formula,
能讓我變成一個噴火大蜥蜴  想變就變
that can turn me into a fire-breathing lizard at will.
但她說這"不是科學"
But she says that's "Not science."
真的不是
It's really not.
那我猜我讓山葵
Yeah, and I guess the shrink ray
幫我研究的縮小射線也不是"科學"咯
I asked Wasabi for isn't "Science" either.
-是嗎  -不是
- Is it? - Nope.
好吧  那"隱形三明治"呢
Well, then, what about "Invisible sandwich"?
-宏  -試想一下  你在吃三明治
- Hiro. - Imagine eating a sandwich,
但所有人都覺得你瘋了
but everybody just thinks you're crazy.
打住吧
Just stop.
-鐳射眼呢  -什么
- Laser eyes? - What?
-痛感手指呢  -別做夢了
- Tingly fingers? - Never gonna happen.
那生長血清呢
Hey, what about a growth serum?
那你在研究什么
So, what have you been working on?
馬上給你看
I'll show you.
布基膠帶嗎
Duct tape?
很不想潑你冷水  哥們
I hate to break it to you, bro.
但已經有人發明了
Already been invented.
老兄
Dude!
好痛
Ow!
這就是我的研究項目
This is what I've been working on.
你好  我叫白球恩
Hello. I am Baymax.
你的個人醫療保健伙伴
Your personal healthcare companion.
我注意到你說"好痛"
I was alerted to the need
表示你需要醫療護理
for medical attention when you said, "Ow."
機器人護士
A robotic nurse.
請用一級到十級表示你現在的疼痛等級
On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate your pain?
生理上還是心理上的疼痛
Physical or emotional?
現在我將掃描你
I will scan you now.
掃描完畢
Scan complete.
你的小臂上有輕度表皮擦傷
You have a slight epidermal abrasion on your forearm.
建議使用抗菌噴霧
I suggest an anti-bacterial spray.
噴霧里的具體成分有什么
What's in the spray, specifically?
主要成分是桿菌肽
The primary ingredient is Bacitracin.
真不巧  我對那個過敏
That's a bummer. I'm actually allergic to that.
你并不對桿菌肽過敏
You are not allergic to bacitracin.
倒是對花生有輕度過敏
You do have a mild allergy to peanuts.
不錯嘛
Not bad.
你給這家伙編程下了不少功夫啊
You've done some serious coding on this thing, huh?
給他編設了超過一萬種醫療措施
Programed him with over 10,000 medical procedures.
濱田正
有了這個芯片才能叫他白求恩
This chip is what makes Baymax, Baymax.
乙烯樹脂嗎
Vinyl?
想設計成無害友善的東西
Yeah, going for a non-threatening, huggable kind of thing.
看著像個會走路的棉花糖
Looks like a walking marshmallow.
-無意冒犯  -我是個機器人
- No offense. - I am a robot.
不會被冒犯
I cannot be offended.
-高光譜相機嗎  -沒錯
- Hyperspectral cameras? -Yep.
-鈦合金支架嗎  -碳纖維
- Titanium skeleton? - Carbon fiber.
對  這樣更輕
Right. Even lighter.
超強制動機  你都是從哪搞到這些的
Killer actuators. Where did you get those?
都是實驗室里研制出來的
Machined them right here, in-house.
-真的嗎  -沒錯
- Really? - Yup.
他能舉起一千磅的重物[450公斤]
He can lift 1,000 pounds.
不是吧
Shut up.
你表現得很好  給你個棒棒糖
You have been a good boy. Have a lollipop.
真好
Nice.
在你沒對我的服務表示滿意之前
I cannot deactivate until you say
我無法進入休眠
you are satisfied with your care.
那好  我對你的服務表示滿意
Well then, I'm satisfied with my care.
他能幫助很多人
He's going to help a lot of people.
他用的是什么電池
Hey, what kind of battery does it use?
鋰電池
Lithium ion.
超級電容器充電更快
You know, supercapacitors would charge way faster.
又在點燈熬油啦  濱田先生
Burning the midnight oil, Mr. Hamada?
你好  教授
Hey, Professor.
我正準備收工呢
Actually, I was just finishing up.
你就是宏了吧
You must be Hiro.
機器人競技者  是吧
Bot-fighter, right?
我女兒小時候也喜歡這個
When my daughter was younger, that's all she wanted to do.
我能看看嗎
May I?
當然
Sure.
磁軸承伺服系統
Magnetic-bearing servos.
很厲害吧
Pretty sick, huh?
想看看我是怎么把它組裝起來的嗎
Wanna see how I put 'em together?
大天才
Hey, genius!
這是他發明的
He invented them.
你就是羅伯特·卡拉翰嗎
You're Robert Callaghan?
就是
Like, as in,
卡拉翰樣條函數
the Callaghan-catmull spline,
和卡拉翰"機器人學定律"的那個卡拉翰嗎
and Callaghan's "Laws of robotics"?
沒錯
That's right.
想過申請這所學校嗎
Ever think about applying here?
年齡不是問題
Your age wouldn't be an issue.
我不知道
I don't know.
他可是一門心思投身機器人競技事業呢
He's pretty serious about his career in bot-fighting.
也沒特別當回事
Well, kind of serious.
能看出來
I can see why.
你的機器人獲勝肯定小菜一碟
With your bot, winning must come easy.
是吧
Yeah, I guess.
你要喜歡簡單的事物
Well, if you like things easy,
我的專業就不適合你
then my program isn't for you.
我們在這里是為了突破機器人學的極限
We push the boundaries of robotics here.
我的學生都將塑造未來
My students go on to shape the future.
很高興認識你  宏
Nice to meet you, Hiro.
祝你旗開得勝
Good luck with the bot-fights.
你要還想競技就得趕緊了
We gotta hurry if you want to catch that bot-fight.
我一定要上這里
I have to go here.
要是我不上這個書呆學校
If I don't go to this nerd school,
我會瘋的
I'm gonna lose my mind.
我怎么才能被錄取
How do I get in?
舊京山理工學院作品展
每年學校都會舉行學生作品展示
Every year, the school has a student showcase.
你要是能想出讓卡拉翰瞠目的作品
You come up with something that blows Callaghan away,
就能進了
you're in.
但作品一定要很厲害
But, it's gotta be great.
舊京山理工學院作品展
相信我
Trust me.
肯定會
It will be.
一片空白
Nothing!
什么靈感都沒有  沒用的渣大腦
No ideas! Useless, empty brain!
十四歲就自暴自棄了
Wow. Washed up at 14.
真可悲
So sad.
什么都想不到  完了  肯定進不去了
I got nothing! I'm done. I'm never getting in.
我才不會放棄你呢
Hey, I'm not giving up on you.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
搖擺一下
Shake things up.
用你聰明的大腦找出方法
Use that big brain of yours to think your way out.
-什么  -換個新角度
- What? - Look for a new angle.
今天這里有很多新玩意兒啊
Wow, a lot of sweet tech here today.
感覺怎么樣
How are you feeling?
你是在跟前機器人競技者說話呢
You're talking to an ex-bot fighter.
要比這更厲害才能讓我緊張
Takes a lot more than this to rattle me.
他確實緊張
Yep, he's nervous.
沒什么好害怕的  小家伙
You have nothing to fear, little fellow.
-他好緊張  -不  我沒有
- He's so tense. - No, I'm not.
放松些  宏
Relax, Hiro.
你的作品很棒  對吧  速美子
Your tech is amazing. Tell him, Go go.
別發牢騷了  拿出點氣概
Stop whining. Woman up.
我沒事
I'm fine!
小伙  你需要什么  除臭劑  薄荷糖
What do you need, little man? Deodorant? Breath mint?
新內褲
Fresh pair of underpants?
內褲嗎  你真的需要些特殊幫助
Underpants? You need serious help.
我是有備而來
Hey, I come prepared.
我六個月都沒洗過衣服了
I haven't done laundry in six months.
一條內褲能穿四天
One pair lasts me four days.
正面穿完反面穿
I go front, I go back,
臟了翻面還能穿
I go inside-out. Then I go front and back.
那真是又惡心又棒極了
Wow. That is both disgusting and awesome.
別鼓勵他了
Don't encourage him.
這叫做"循環利用"
It's called "Recycling."
下一個展示者  濱田宏
Next presenter, Hiro Hamada.
太好了  到你了
Oh, yeah. This is it.
我想我該上場了
I guess I'm up.
快來拍照  大家一起說"宏"
Okay, photo, photo! Everybody say, "Hiro."
-宏  -太棒了
- Hiro! - Yeah!
我們愛你  宏  祝你好運
We love you, Hiro. Good luck!
-別搞砸了  -祝好運  小伙
- Don't mess it up. - Break a leg, little man.
科學  太棒了
Science, yeah!
好了  伙計  該上場了
All right, bro. This is it.
快來  別不理我呀
Come on. Don't leave me hanging.
怎么了
What's going on?
我真的很想來這里上學
I really want to go here.
你能行的
You got this.
我是宏...
My name is Hiro...
對不起
Sorry.
我叫濱田宏
My name is Hiro Hamada,
我做了些我覺得非常酷的東西
and I've been working on something that I think is pretty cool.
希望你們會喜歡
I hope you like it.
這是一個微型機器人
This is a microbot.
深呼吸
Breathe.
看起來很不起眼
It doesn't look like much,
但當它跟其它同伴連在一起的時候
but when it links up with the rest of its pals,
事情就會變得有趣起來
things get a little more interesting.
微型機器人都由這個神經傳遞器來控制
The microbots are controlled with this neural transmitter.
我想讓它們做什么
I think what I want them to do...
他們就會做什么
They do it.
這個技術能應用于無限領域
The applications for this tech are limitless.
建筑物
Construction.
過去需要團隊手工合作
What used to take teams of people working by hand
幾個月或者幾年的工程
for months or years,
現在只需要一個人就能完成
can now be accomplished by one person.
而這還只是個開始
And that's just the beginning.
交通應用怎么樣
How about transportation?
微型機器人可以輕松將任何東西移動到
Microbots can move anything anywhere,
任何地方
with ease.
只要你能想到  微型機器人就能做到
If you can think it, the microbots can do it.
唯一的局限就是你的想象力
The only limit is your imagination.
微型機器人
Microbots!
那是我的外甥
That's my nephew!
太棒了
Yes!
我的家人  我愛我的家人
My family! I love my family!
太棒了
Nailed it!
-你做到了  -不錯嘛
- You did it! - Not bad!
真令我大開眼界  伙計
Yeah! You just blew my mind, dude!
他們很愛你  太了不起了
They loved you. That was amazing!
是的
Yes.
再開發一下  你的技術會是革命性的
With some development, your tech could be revolutionary.
阿里斯特·克瑞
Alistair Krei!
我能看一下嗎
May I?
真了不起
Extraordinary.
我想要你的微型機器人加入克瑞科技
I want your microbots at Krei Tech.
不會吧
Shut up.
克瑞先生說的對
Mr. Krei is right.
你的微型機器人是一項創新技術
Your microbots are an inspired piece of tech.
你可以繼續開發它們
You can continue to develop them,
或者將它們賣給
or you can sell them to a man
一個完全自私自利的人
who's only guided by his own self-interest.
羅伯特  我知道你是怎么看我的
Robert, I know how you feel about me,
但那不應該影響到...
but it shouldn't affect...
這是你的決定  宏
This is your decision, Hiro.
但你應該知道
But you should know
克瑞先生習慣于走捷徑并忽視可靠的科學
Mr. Krei has cut corners and ignored sound science
以達到自己的目的
to get where he is.
那不是真的
That's just not true.
對克瑞科技持有你的微型機器人
I wouldn't trust Krei Tech
或是任何東西
with your microbots,
我表示不信任
or anything else.
宏  我會給你
Hiro, I'm offering you
任何十四歲少年都無法想象的金錢
more money than any 14-year-old could imagine.
很感謝你的邀請  克瑞先生
I appreciate the offer, Mr. Krei,
但它們不出售
but they're not for sale.
我以為你會做出明智的決定
I thought you were smarter than that.
羅伯特
Robert.
克瑞先生
Mr. Krei.
那是我弟弟的
That's my brother's.
是啊
That's right.
很期待在課堂上見到你
I look forward to seeing you in class.
太不可思議了
Unbelievable!
我就說過嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
好了  天才們
All right, geniuses,
讓我們填飽饑餓的大腦吧
let's feed those hungry brains.
回餐館去
Back to the cafe!
晚飯我請客
Dinner is on me!
太棒了  沒什么比免費的食物更好了
Yes! Nothing is better than free food!
-凱斯嬸嬸  -除非是發霉的
- Aunt Cass? - Unless it's moldy.
我們稍后就到  好嗎
We'll... we'll catch up, okay?
當然  我太為你驕傲了
Sure. I'm so proud of you.
你們兩個都是
Both of you.
謝謝  凱斯嬸嬸
Thanks, Aunt Cass.
我知道你要說什么
I know what you're going to say.
我應該為自己感到驕傲
"I should be proud of myself,"
因為我終于用天賦做了些重要的事
"because I'm finally using my gift for something important."
沒有沒有  我只是想說
No, no. I was just gonna
你的飛行是整個展示的低潮
tell you your fly was down for the whole show.
哈哈  太搞笑了
Ha-ha-hilarious.
你說什么
What?
歡迎來書呆學校  書呆子
Welcome to nerd school, nerd.
我...
Hey, I...
要不是你  我也不會在這里  所以
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't for you. So,
你懂的
you know,
非常感謝你沒有放棄我
thanks for not giving up on me.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
是的  我沒事
Yeah. I'm okay.
但是卡拉翰教授還在里面
But Professor Callaghan is still in there.
正  不要
Tadashi, no!
卡拉翰在里面
Callaghan's in there.
得有人去幫忙
Someone has to help.
正
Tadashi!
給  喝點茶
Here. Have some tea.
親愛的
Hey, sweetie.
凱斯嬸嬸
Hey, Aunt Cass.
松田女士在餐廳里
Mrs. Matsuda's in the cafe.
穿了件完全不適合80歲老人穿的衣服
She's wearing something super inappropriate for an 80-year-old.
說這個總能把你逗笑
That always cracks you up.
你該下樓來
You should come down.
晚會兒吧
Maybe later.
學校又打電話來了
The university called again.
已經開課幾周了
It's been a few weeks since classes started.
但他們說現在去注冊還不晚
But they said it's not too late to register.
好的  謝謝  我會考慮的
Okay. Thanks. I'll think about it.
機器人競技
嘿  宏
Hey, Hiro.
我們只是想看看你怎么樣了
We just wanted to check in, and see how you're doing.
我們希望你能在這里  伙計
We wish you were here, buddy.
宏  如果我現在能擁有一項超能力
Hiro, if I could have only one superpower right now,
我希望是能從攝像頭里爬出去
it would be the ability to crawl through this camera,
給你一個大大的擁抱
and give you a big hug.
好痛
Ow!
你好  我是白球恩
Hello. I am Baymax,
你的個人醫療保健伙伴
your personal healthcare companion.
白球恩
Hey, Baymax.
我不知道你還能工作
I didn't know you were still active.
我感受到了傷感的情緒
I heard a sound of distress.
有什么麻煩事嗎
What seems to be the trouble?
我只是不小心踢到腳趾頭
I just stubbed my toe a little.
我沒事
I'm fine.
請用一級到十級來表示你的疼痛等級
On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate your pain?
零級  我沒事  真的
A zero. I'm okay, really.
謝謝  你可以縮回去了
Thanks. You can shrink now.
我要碰一下會疼嗎
Does it hurt when I touch it?
沒事兒的  你別碰
That's okay. No touching.
我很好
I'm fine...
你摔倒了
You have fallen.
你以為呢
You think?
-以一級到...  -好痛
- On a scale of 1 to... - Ow!
以一級...
On a scale...
On a sca...
以一級到十級...
On a scale of 1 to 10...
請用一級到十級來表示你的疼痛等級
On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate your pain?
零級
Zero.
-你可以哭出來  -不  不
- It is all right to cry. - No. No, no, no, no.
哭泣是對疼痛的自然反應
Crying is a natural response to pain.
我沒有要哭
I'm not crying.
-我會掃描你查看傷情  -別掃描我
- I will scan you for injuries. - Don't scan me.
-掃描完畢  -不可理喻
- Scan complete. - Unbelievable.
你沒有受傷
You have sustained no injuries.
但是你的荷爾蒙和神經遞質水平
However, your hormone and neurotransmitter levels
表明你在經歷一些情緒波動
indicate that you are experiencing mood swings,
這在青春期很常見
common in adolescence.
診斷結果為青春期
Diagnosis, puberty.
什么
What?
好了  是時候縮回去了
Okay. Time to shrink now.
你會經歷體毛的增加
You should expect an increase in body hair,
特別是在你的臉上  胸前  腋窩還有
especially on your face, chest, armpits, and...
謝謝你  夠了
Thank you! That's enough.
你還會經歷一些奇怪但很強烈的欲望
You may also experience strange and powerful new urges.
好了  回到你的箱子里去吧
Okay! Let's get you back in your luggage.
在你沒對我的服務表示滿意之前
I cannot deactivate until you say
我無法進入休眠
you are satisfied with your care.
好吧  我很滿意我的...
Fine. I'm satisfied with my...
那是我的微型機器人嗎
My microbot?
這沒道理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
對于要過渡到成年階段的青少年來說
Puberty can often be a confusing time
青春期通常是讓人感到迷惑的
for a young adolescent flowering into manhood.
不  這東西應該被其它微型機器人吸引
No. The thing is attracted to the other microbots,
但那不可能
but that's impossible.
它們都在大火里被毀掉了
They were destroyed in the fire.
這個蠢東西壞掉了
Dumb thing's broken.
你的小機器人想要去哪里
Your tiny robot is trying to go somewhere.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
你干脆找一下它想去哪兒吧
Why don't you find out where it's trying to go?
那會穩定你青春期的情緒波動嗎
Would that stabilize your pubescent mood swings?
當然了
Absolutely.
白球恩
Baymax?
搞什么
What?
-宏  -嘿  凱斯嬸嬸
- Hiro? - Hey, Aunt Cass!
你起來了  而且
Wow. You're up and...
是啊  我想是時候了
Yeah! I figured it was time.
你要去學校注冊嗎
Are you registering for school?
是的
Yes.
我考慮了你說的  確實啟發了我
I thought about what you said. Really inspired me.
親愛的  那太好了
Oh, honey, that's so great.
好了
Okay,
今晚給你準備特別大餐
special dinner tonight.
我會準備些雞翅
I'll whip up some chicken wings.
涂上辣醬  辣到你臉都麻
You know, with the hot sauce that makes our faces numb.
-聽起來不錯  -就這么定了
- Okay, sounds good. - Great!
最后抱抱
Last hug.
白球恩
Baymax!
看路
Watch it!
白球恩
Baymax!
你瘋了嗎  你在干什么
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
我在找你的小機器人想去哪兒
I have found where your tiny robot wants to go.
我說過它壞掉了  它沒想去...
I told you, it's broken. It's not trying to go...
鎖上了
Locked.
那里有個窗戶
There is a window.
請小心些
Please exercise caution.
從這個高度摔下會造成肢體損傷
A fall from this height could lead to bodily harm.
不好了
Oh, no.
稍等  我放些氣出來
Excuse me while I let out some air.
你好了嗎
Are you done?
是的
Yes.
重新充氣還需要一會兒
It will take me a moment to re-inflate.
好吧  小點兒聲就行
Fine, just keep it down.
這不是我的微型機器人嗎
My microbots?
有人在大量生產
Someone's making more.
宏
Hiro?
你把我的心臟病都嚇出來了
You gave me a heart attack!
我的雙手可以用作除顫器  請離手
My hands are equipped with defibrillators. Clear.
停下  快停下  只是一種形容而已
Stop, stop, stop! It's just an expression.
不好了
Oh, no.
快跑
Run!
快點
Oh, come on!
我走不快
I am not fast.
果然沒騙我
Yeah, no kidding!
快走  快點
Go! Go! Come on.
把門踢開
Kick it down!
那砸開
Then punch it!
快走  快走
Go! Go!
快點  快走
Oh, come on! Go, go, go!
快下去
Move it!
快點
Come on!
不  不
No, no.
快點兒  去窗戶那里
Come on! The window!
快擠過去
Suck it in!
白球恩
Baymax!
宏
Hiro?
快  咱們快離開這兒
Come on, let's get out of here.
走  快點
Go! Hurry!
好吧  讓我先搞清楚
All right, let me get this straight.
一個戴著歌舞伎面具的男人追殺你們
A man in a kabuki mask attacked you,
他還有一支微型飛行機器人大軍
with an army of miniature flying robots.
是微型機器人
"Microbots."
-微型機器人  -對
-Microbots. -Yeah.
他利用神經傳遞器
He was controlling them
通過心靈感應來控制它們
telepathically with a neurocranial transmitter.
也就是說  這位歌舞伎先生
So, Mr. Kabuki was using esp
是在用超能力來追殺你和氣球人
to attack you and balloon man.
你的飛行機器人被偷時你沒來備案嗎
Did you file a report when your flying robots were stolen?
沒  我以為它們已經燒毀了
No. I thought they were all destroyed.
我知道這聽著挺扯的
Look, I know it sounds crazy,
不過當時白球恩也在
but Baymax was there, too.
-和他講講  -好的  警官
-Tell him. -Yes, officer.
他說的是真...
He's telling the truth.
你這是...怎么了
What the... What's wrong with you?
電量低
Low battery.
你得挺住
Try to keep it together.
我是白球恩  你的個人醫療保健伙伴
I'm healthcare, your personal Baymax companion.
孩子  不如我給你父母打個電話
Kid, how about we call your parents,
叫他們來一趟好了
and get them down here?
什么
What?
把你的姓名和電話寫在這兒
Write your name and number down
這樣我們就可以...
on this piece of paper, and we can...
我得把你弄回家  放到充電座上
I've gotta get you home to your charging station.
你還能走嗎
Can you walk?
我將對你進行掃描  掃描完畢
I will scan you now. Scan complete.
醫療保健
Healthcare.
好了
Okay.
我嬸嬸問起  就說整天在學校  懂嗎
If my aunt asks, we were at school all day. Got it?
我們還跳窗戶了呢
We jumped out a window.
別  小點聲
No! Quiet!
我們還跳窗戶了呢
We jumped out a window.
在凱斯嬸嬸面前可不能提那些事
You can't say things like that around aunt Cass.
宏
Hiro?
你回來了  親愛的
You home, sweetie?
是啊
That's right.
我就說我聽見你了嘛
I thought I heard you.
凱斯嬸嬸
Hey, aunt Cass.
看看我的小大學生
Look at my little college man.
我都等不急要聽了
I can't wait to hear all about it!
雞翅馬上就好
And wings are almost ready.
哦耶
Whee!
你別出聲
Will you be quiet?
是啊  雞翅  哦耶
Yeah, wings! Whee!
好了  準備辣到你臉都麻了嗎
All right, get ready to have your face melted.
吃完明天可就不好受了
We are gonna feel these things tomorrow.
懂我的意思嗎
You know what I'm saying?
好了
Okay.
快坐下  給我講講
Sit down. Tell me everything.
問題是  我太晚去報到
The thing is that, since I registered so late,
所以還有好多事情要弄
I've got a lot of school stuff to catch up on.
什么動靜
What was that?
摩奇
Mochi.
那該死的貓
That darn cat.
至少吃點再上去  好嗎
At least take a plate for the road, okay?
-別學得太...-多謝關心
-Don't work too... -Thanks for understanding.
毛毛球  毛毛球
Hairy baby. Hairy baby.
好了  來吧
All right, come on.
我是醫療保健  你的個人白球恩伙伴
I'm healthcare, your personal baymax companion.
一只腳先邁進去
One foot in front of the other.
這沒道理啊
This doesn't make any sense.
正
Tadashi.
什么
What?
正
Tadashi.
正走了
Tadashi's gone.
那他什么時候回來
When will he return?
他死了  白球恩
He's dead, baymax.
正身體很好啊
Tadashi was in excellent health.
合理飲食而且注重鍛煉
With a proper diet and exercise,
應該活得很久才對
he should have lived a long life.
是啊  本該是的
Yeah, he should have.
可是一場大火...
But there was a fire and...
現在  他已經不在了
Now, he's gone.
-正在這里  -不
-Tadashi is here. -No.
人們總是說他沒有真的離開
People keep saying he's not really gone.
只要我們還想著他
As long as we remember him.
就還是會疼
It still hurts.
你的身體上未發現有損傷
I see no evidence of physical injury.
那是另一種疼
It's a different kind of hurt.
你是我的患者
You are my patient.
我愿意幫忙
I would like to help.
這個你治不了  伙計
You can't fix this one, buddy.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我在下載有關于你的缺失數據
I am downloading a database on personal loss.
數據庫下載完畢
Database downloaded.
診斷
喪親之痛
治療方案
治療方法包括聯系你的親朋好友
Treatments include contact with friends and loved ones.
聯系家人與朋友
我正在聯系他們
I am contacting them now.
別  別  別聯系他們
No, no, no! I... Don't do that.
已聯系你的朋友
Your friends have been contacted.
真是的
Unbelievable.
你這是干嘛
Now, what are you doing?
其它治療包括同情和肢體撫慰
Other treatments include compassion and physical reassurance.
我沒事  真的
I'm okay. Really.
會好起來的  好了  好了
You will be all right. There, there.
謝謝  白球恩
Thanks, Baymax.
關于火災的事我很遺憾
I am sorry about the fire.
沒事啦  那是個意外
It's okay. It was an accident.
除非...
Unless...
除非那不是意外
Unless it wasn't.
在作品展上
At the showcase,
那個戴面具的家伙偷走我的微型機器人
that guy in the mask stole my microbots. And...
然后放火來掩人耳目
And then set the fire to cover his tracks.
他該對正的死負責
He's responsible for Tadashi.
我們得去抓住那家伙
We gotta catch that guy.
它是活的
It's alive!
它是活的  它是活的  它是活的
It's alive, it's alive! It's alive!
要想抓住他
If we're gonna catch that guy,
你得升升級
you need some upgrades.
抓住那個戴面具的男人
Will apprehending the man
會改善你的情緒狀態嗎
in the mask improve your emotional state?
當然會
Absolutely.
先改進一下你的身手
Let's work on your moves.
現在  來處理一下這里
Now, let's take care of this.
我有個疑慮
I have some concerns.
這盔甲可能會破壞掉我這無害抱抱的設計
This armor may undermine my non-threatening, huggable design.
要的就是這樣  伙計
That's kind of the idea, buddy.
sick有不舒服之意
你帥慘了
You look sick.
我不可能不舒服  我是個機器人
I cannot be sick. I am a robot.
只是一種形容而已
It's just an expression.
數據轉移完畢
Data transfer complete.
濱田正
我沒覺得
I fail to see
空手道能讓我成為更稱職的醫療保健伙伴
how karate makes me a better healthcare companion.
你希望我健康  不是嗎
You want to keep me healthy, don't you?
朝這兒打
Punch this.
太棒了  錘拳
Yes! Hammerfist!
側踢
Side kick!
手刀
Knifehand!
后踢
Back kick!
小熊軟糖
Gummy bears!
太好了
Yes!
來  頂個拳
Yeah! Fist bump!
我的搏擊數據庫沒有頂拳這招
"Fist bump" Is not in my fighting database.
不  這個和搏擊沒關系
No, this isn't a fighting thing.
當人們興奮或者是激動的時候
It's what people do sometimes
就會頂拳
when they're excited or pumped up.
看  這不就會了嘛
Hey, now you're getting it.
我會將"頂拳"添加到我的關愛矩陣中
I will add "Fist bump" to my care-giving matrix.
好了  我們去找那家伙吧
All right. Let's go get that guy.
快來
Come on!
拿下他  白球恩
Get him, Baymax!
我們來晚了
We're too late.
你的小機器人好像想去哪里
Your tiny robot is trying to go somewhere.
來
Come on.
建議飯后一小時再游泳
Always wait one hour after eating before swimming.
快跑
Come on!
你的心跳急劇加快...
Your heart rate has increased dramatic...
好了  白球恩  你升的級該派上用場了
Okay, Baymax, time to use those upgrades.
-宏  -不  別過來
-Hiro? -No, no, no!
離開這兒  快走
Get out of here! Go!
哥們  你在這干什么呢
Dude, what are you doing out here?
沒干什么  就是隨便走走
Nothing! Just out for a walk.
緩解一下青春期的情緒波動
Helps my pubescent mood swings.
那是白球恩嗎
Is that Baymax?
是的  你們真不用...
Yeah, but you really...
他為什么穿著碳纖維內褲
Why is he wearing carbon fiber underpants?
我還會空手道呢
I also know karate.
你們得走了
You guys need to go.
別拒我們千里之外  宏
No, don't push us away, Hiro.
我們愿意幫你
We're here for you.
白球恩聯系我們也是因為這個
That's why Baymax contacted us.
痛失至親的人
Those who suffer a loss,
需要來自親朋好友的支持
require support from friends and loved ones.
好吧  可我...
Okay, but I...
誰愿意跟我們先來分享他的感受
Who would like to share their feelings first?
我來
I'll go. Okay.
我叫弗雷迪  我快有三十天...
My name is Fred, and it has been 30 days since my last...
我的媽啊
Holy mother of megazon!
我是不是眼花了
Am I the only one seeing this?
老天爺  不要
Oh, my gosh! Oh, no!
快跑
Go!
抓住他  白球恩
Baymax, get him!
別  別  別  你這是干嘛
No, no, no, no, no! What are you doing?
我這是救你命
I'm saving your life.
白球恩能搞定他
Baymax can handle that guy!
不好了
Oh, no.
山葵
Wasabi!
拜拜
Goodbye!
宏  快說清楚  馬上
Hiro. Explanation. Now.
他偷了我的微型機器人  還放了火
He stole my microbots. He started the fire.
我不知道他是誰
I don't know who he is!
白球恩  掌根推擊
Baymax, palm-heel strike!
左轉
Hard left!
看那面具  那身黑衣服
That mask, the black suit...
我們正在被超級大反派追殺  同志們
We're under attack from a super villain, people!
看  多酷
I mean, how cool is that?
確實是挺危險  不過  實在太酷了
I mean, it's scary, obviously. But how cool!
怎么停了
Why are we stopped?
紅燈
The light's red!
追車戲哪來的紅燈
There are no red lights in a car chase!
他為什么要殺我們
Why is he trying to kill us?
你為什么要殺我們
Why are you trying to kill us?
這種典型的反派看得多了
It's classic villain. We've seen too much!
我們別冒下結論
Let's not jump to conclusions.
沒人說他要殺我們
We don't know he's trying to kill us.
小心
Car!
他是要殺我們
He's trying to kill us!
你剛剛是打轉向燈了嗎
Did you just put your blinker on?
你得表明你是要轉彎啊
You have to indicate your turn!
要遵守交通規則
It's the law!
夠了
That's it.
停車
Stop the car!
我和白球恩可以對付他
Baymax and I can take this guy!
時刻系好安全帶
Seatbelts save lives.
安全才能時刻在
Buckle up, every time.
你干什么  你干什么
What are you doing? What are you doing?
-甩掉他了嗎  -小心
-Did we lose him? -Look out!
白球恩  抓緊
Baymax, hold on!
-我們完了  -我們能行
-We're not gonna make it! -We're gonna make it!
成功了  耶
We made it! Yes!
我說了我們能行
I told you we'd make it!
你的傷口需要檢查
Your injuries require my attention.
而且你的體溫過低
And your body temperatures are low.
我們得趕緊離開
We should get out of here.
我知道個地方
I know a place.
這是哪兒
Where are we?
弗雷迪
Fred.
你這是去哪兒
Where are you going?
歡迎來到"米卡薩"
Welcome to mi casa.
"米卡薩"實際為西語而非法語
是法語里"前門"的意思
That's French for "Front door."
其實不是
It's really not.
聽著  二貨
Listen, nitwit.
剛剛才有個戴面具的瘋子要殺我們
A lunatic in a mask just tried to kill us.
我可沒心情...
I'm not in the mood for any...
歡迎回家  弗雷德里克少爺
Welcome home, master Frederick.
好哥們  希斯克里夫
Heathcliff, my man!
大伙快進來  在這兒會很安全
Come on in, guys. We'll be safe in here.
頂一個
Gimme some.
弗雷迪
Freddie,
這是你家
this is your house?
我以為你住在橋洞底下呢
I thought you lived under a bridge.
確切的說  是我父母的
Well, technically, it belongs to my parents.
他們正在我家的小島上度假呢
They're on a vacay on the family island.
其實我們什么時候也該去一趟  好好玩玩
You know, we should totally go some time. Frolic.
你這是逗我呢
You gotta be kidding me.
弗雷迪  別碰我
要不是我剛剛被一個面具男追殺
If I wasn't just attacked by a guy in a kabuki mask,
這絕對是我今天見到的最不可思議的事
I think this would be the weirdest thing I've seen today.
簡直看不下去了
My brain hates my eyes for seeing this.
你的體溫仍然很低
Your body temperature is still low.
是啊
Yeah.
就像抱著一大塊暖暖的棉花糖
It's like spooning a warm marshmallow.
真棒
It's so nice.
哦  又暖又舒服
Oh, yeah, that's toasty.
乖機器人
Good robot.
有人認識這個符號嗎
Does this symbol mean anything to you guys?
-是只鳥  -不
-Yes! It's a bird! -No!
面具男拿的東西上
The guy in the mask was carrying something
有這個符號
with this symbol on it.
抓住那個戴面具的人
Apprehending the man in
會改善宏的情緒狀態
the mask will improve Hiro's emotional state.
抓住他
Apprehend him?
我們都不知道他是誰
We don't even know who he is.
我有個想法
I have a theory.
"殺人狂博士"
"Dr. Slaughter, md"?
其實是身家百萬的武器設計師
Actually, millionaire weapons designer,
馬爾科姆·查茲提克
Malcolm chazzletick.
"殲滅者"
"The annihilator"?
真實身份  工業家雷德·阿克斯沃西
Behind the mask, industrialist Reid Axworthy.
"馮·破壞男爵"  直接說重點
"Baron Von destruct"? Just get to the point!
你們沒明白嗎
Don't you guys get it?
那個戴面具追殺我們的人
The man in the mask who attacked us
其實就是...
is none other than...
瞧
Voila!
阿里斯特·克瑞
Alistair krei.
-什么  -你想想
-What? -Think about it.
克瑞想要你的微型機器人  你不給
Krei wanted your microbots, and you said no.
但是像他這樣的人不會就此善罷甘休
But rules don't apply to a man like krei.
不可能  他人這么高調
There's no way. The guy is too high profile.
那么那個人是誰
Then who was that guy in the mask?
我不知道
I don't know.
我們對他一無所知
We don't know anything about him.
那個人是AB型陰性血
His blood type is ab-negative.
-體內膽固醇含量...-白球恩
-Cholesterol levels are... - Baymax,
你掃描他了
you scanned him?
程序設定要求我評估每個人的健康需求
I am programed to assess everyone's healthcare needs.
太棒了
Yes!
我用這個數據就能把他揪出來了
I can use the data from your scan to find him.
所以你是打算花一輩子的時間
You'd have to scan everyone in San fransokyo.
來掃描舊京山的每個人
That might take, I don't know, forever.
不  不  不  我...
No, no, no, no. I...
我只是需要換個角度來思考
I just have to look for another angle.
有了
Got it!
只要升級了白球恩的傳感器
I'll scan the whole city at the same time.
我就能一次性掃描全城的人
I just have to upgrade Baymax's sensor.
事實上  要想抓住那家伙
Actually, if we're gonna catch this guy,
你們都得來次大改造
I need to upgrade all of you.
你說改造誰
Upgrade who, now?
痛失至親的人
Those who suffer a loss
需要來自親朋好友的支持
require support from friends and loved ones.
這個節奏我喜歡
Okay, I like where this is heading!
我們這群書呆子可對付不了那家伙
We can't go against that guy! We're nerds!
宏  我們很想幫你
Hiro, we want to help,
可我們就只是我們
but we're just us.
不
No.
你們的能耐可不止這些
You can be way more.
濱田正是我們的摯友
Tadashi Hamada was our best friend.
就聽你的了
We're in.
你們有這種感覺嗎  伙計們
Can you feel it? You guys, do you feel this?
我們即將書寫自己的故事
Our origin story begins.
我們就要成為超級英雄了
We're gonna be superheroes!
手抬起來
Arms up.
神經傳遞器一定藏在他面具里
The neurotransmitter must be in his mask.
面具一旦到手  他就沒轍了
We get the mask, and he can't control the bots.
游戲結束
Game over.
旁人笑我太平凡
They say "We are what we are"
可不必就此認命
But we don't have to be
我舉止乖張
I'm bad behavior
可我仍會傾盡全力
But I do it in the best way
永恒之火熊熊燃燒
I'll be the watcher
我將靜觀其變
Of the eternal flame
你們狂熱的夢想
I'll be the guard dog
由我來保駕護航
Of all your fever dreams
我就是那沙漏底部的點點細砂
I am the sand in the bottom half of the hourglass
因為我們終將成為不朽
Cause we could be immortals
成為不朽
Immortals
就在不久之后
Just not for long for long
放下過去種種恩怨
Live with me forever now
攜手并進共同向前
Pull the blackout curtains down
就在不久之后
Just not for long for long
我們終將成為不朽
We could be immortals
成為不朽
Immortals
有時心存信仰的唯一回報
Sometimes the only payoff for having any faith
源于歷經重重考驗后仍在我心
Is when it's tested again and again every day
我依舊將你的過去比作我的未來
I'm still comparing your past to my future
因為我們終將成為不朽
Cause we could be immortals
成為不朽
Immortals
就在不久之后
Just not for long for long
超級彈跳
Super jump!
放下過去種種恩怨
Pull the blackout curtains down
-我能噴火啦  -就在不久之后
-I breathe fire. -Just not for long for long
我們終將成為不朽
We could be immortals
載入史詩
Immortals
書寫傳奇
成為不朽
Immortals
我愛死這身了
I love it!
還行吧
Not bad.
你們的衣服都很合身嗎
Anybody else's suit riding up on them?
伙計們
Hey, guys!
來看看這個
Check this out.
很榮幸為你們介紹
I'd like to introduce,
二代白球恩
Baymax 2.0.
帥呆了
He's glorious.
好啦  集中注意力
Hold up. Focus.
給他們露一手  老兄
Show 'em what you got, buddy.
拳頭啊  讓他們見識下那個拳頭
The fist, show them the fist.
不  不是這個
No, not that.
是那個  另外那個
The thing, the other thing.
火箭飛拳讓弗雷迪開心極了
Rocket fist make Freddie so happy!
新特性還不止這個
That's just one of his new upgrades!
白球恩  展開雙翼
Baymax, wings.
不是吧
No way!
推進器準備
Thrusters.
我沒覺得飛行
I fail to see how flying
能讓我成為更稱職的醫療保健伙伴
makes me a better healthcare companion.
我更不明白你為什么不覺得這個贊爆了
I fail to see how you fail to see that it's awesome!
全速推進
Full thrust.
穩住了  大塊頭
Steady, big guy.
不著急  慢慢來
Look, let's just take this slow.
起來  起來  起來
Up, up, up, up, up!
向上推進  向上推進
Thrust, thrust, thrust!
過頭了  過頭了
Too much thrust! Too much thrust!
推進過頭了
Too much thrust!
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no!
別熄火  別熄火
Back on! Back on!
別  別  別
On! On! On!
起來  起來  起來
Go up! Up, up, up!
我的天
Oh, man!
今天算是飛夠了
Maybe... Maybe enough flying for today.
你說呢
What do you say?
你的神經遞質激素水平正穩步上升
Your neurotransmitter levels are rising steadily.
這說明什么
Which means what?
剛才的治療見效了
The treatment is working.
不
Oh, no!
不  不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no!
別這樣  白球恩
Whoa, Baymax!
太棒了
Yes!
這真是...
That was...
真是...
酷斃了
Sick.
只是一種形容而已
It is just an expression.
你說得對  伙計
That's... that's right, buddy.
我再也不想坐公交了
I am never taking the bus again.
你的情緒狀態有所好轉
Your emotional state has improved.
只要你對服務表示滿意  我隨時能休眠
I can deactivate if you say you are satisfied with your care.
什么
What?
我才不想你休眠
No, I don't want you to deactivate.
我們還沒找到那家伙呢
We still have to find that guy.
好了  啟動超級傳感器吧
So, fire up that super-sensor.
掃描功能已強化
Functionality improved.
搜尋范圍擴大十倍
1000% increase in range.
已找到匹配源
I have found a match,
就在那座島上
on that island.
-風景還不錯  -是啊  如果...
-Killer view. -Yeah. If I...
如果我不恐高的話
If I wasn't terrified of heights,
我應該會喜歡這個
I'd probably love this.
可是我很恐高  所以我一點都不喜歡
But I'm terrified of heights, so I don't love it.
在那兒  白球恩  帶我們過去
There. Baymax, take us in.
棒極了
Awesome!
作戰小分隊的首次著陸
Our first landing together as a team.
走吧  伙計們
Guys, come on.
"隔離區"
"Quarantine"?
你們不會不知道"隔離"是什么意思吧
Do you people know what "Quarantine" Means?
"隔離"
"Quarantine."
是為了防止污染物引起疾病甚至死亡
Enforced isolation to prevent contamination
所采取的一種強制性隔絕手段
that could lead to disease, or, in some cases, death.
標志牌上可有個骷髏頭
There's a skull face on this one.
那可是骷髏頭
A skull face!
別放松警惕
Be ready.
他說不定就在附近
He could be anywhere.
受死吧
Fire!
燒死你  燒死你
Spitting fire! Spitting fire!
只是一只鳥
That was a bird.
至少我們的裝備挺管用的
Well, at least we know our gear works.
鏘鏘六人行
Six intrepid friends
弗雷迪是老大
Led by Fred
老大是弗雷迪
Their leader, Fred
弗雷迪的守護者們
Fred's angels
手持閣樓撿來的古老護身符
Harnessing the power of the sun with the
隨意駕馭太陽的力量
Ancient amulet they found in the attic
護身符是綠的
The amulet is green
說不定是祖母綠
It's probably an emerald
弗雷迪  再唱信不信我劈你臉上
Fred, I will laser-hand you in the face.
伙計們  別出聲
Guys, Shhhh...
有發現他的蹤跡嗎  白球恩
Any sign of him, Baymax?
這幢建筑干擾了我的傳感器
This structure is interfering with my sensor.
棒極了  機器人罷工了
Perfect. The robot's broken.
伙計們  你們可能想看看這個
Guys, you might want to see this.
你覺得這是什么  天才
What do you think it is, genius?
我不確定  可是看那個
I'm not sure. But look.
宏
Hiro.
克瑞
Krei.
這就對了
That's right.
我們的使命就是挑戰不可能
We were asked to do the impossible.
這就是我們的成果
That's what we did.
重新定義傳輸真正的概念
We've reinvented the very concept of transportation.
朋友們  這就是寂靜雀計劃
Friends, I present project Silent Sparrow.
長官  借用一下
General, may I?
魔法帽
Magic hat!
隱形傳輸
Teleportation.
物體通過隱形空間實現實時傳送
The transport of matter instantaneously through space.
再也不只是科幻小說的情節了
Not science fiction anymore.
不過我們斥巨資可不僅僅是為了運送帽子
Now, we didn't spend billions of tax dollars to teleport hats.
女士們先生們  你們即將見證歷史
Ladies and gentlemen, you're here to witness history.
準備好兜風了嗎  艾比蓋爾
Ready to go for a ride, Abigail?
既然請到了這么多人
We've invited all these people.
那就讓他們都開開眼界
Might as well give 'em a show.
發射前倒計時三十秒
T-minus 30 seconds to launch.
-29  28  -阿爾戈號
-29, 28... -This is argo.
-艙體就位  -27...
-Capsule's in position. -27...
先生  我們剛剛檢測到
Sir, we've picked up a slight irregularity
磁控場出現了小范圍的異常波動
in the magnetic containment field.
克瑞先生  出什么問題了嗎
Mr. Krei, is there a problem?
不  當然沒問題
No. No problem.
安全范圍內的參數浮動罷了
It's well within the parameters.
我們繼續
Let's move forward.
三  二  一
3, 2, 1.
座艙氣壓正常
Cabin pressure is go.
機艙發射
Pod engaged.
磁場破裂  立刻停止
Field breach! Abort!
我們和機艙失去聯系了
We've lost all contact with the pod.
不  天啊
Oh, no.
-傳送門在解體  -飛行員失蹤了
-It's breaking up! -The pilot is gone.
二號傳送門已失效
Portal two is down.
磁控場也失效了
The magnetic containment field's down!
克瑞  馬上關掉它
Krei, shut it down now!
封閉全島  禁止進入
I want this island sealed off!
政府叫停了克瑞的項目
The government shut down Krei's experiment.
所以他想用你的微型機器人把機器偷回來
And he's using your microbots to steal his machine back.
克瑞真的是那個面具男
Krei is the guy in the mask.
不好了
Oh, no.
白球恩  帶我們離開這
Baymax, get us out of here.
去搶傳遞器
Go for the transmitter.
就在面具后面
Behind his mask.
白球恩
Baymax!
好了  計劃是什么
All right, what's the plan?
該弗雷迪出場了
It's Fred time.
超級彈跳
Super jump!
重力摧毀
Gravity crush!
急速墜落
Falling hard.
說真的  計劃是什么
Seriously, what is the plan?
-搶面具  -我做你的后盾
-Get the mask. -Right behind you.
開什么玩笑  計劃到底是什么
For real, what is the plan?
你
Hey!
想跳舞嗎  面具男
You want to dance, masked man?
要不就和這個來一曲吧
'Cause you'll be dancing with these.
乖乖交出面具  否則讓你嘗嘗這個
Hand over the mask, or you'll get a taste of this!
還有這個
And a little bit of that!
我干得還不錯
Hey! I did all right.
你就這點能耐嗎
Is that all you got?
還有這一手啊
You got that, too?
看我不燒死你
It's back into the fire!
你完了  克瑞
It's over, Krei.
教...  卡拉翰教授
Pro... Professor Callaghan?
那場爆炸...
The explosion...
你明明死了
You died.
沒死  幸虧你的微型機器人
No. I had your microbots.
可是  正
But, Tadashi.
你就眼看著他送死
You just let him die.
把面具給我  宏
Give me the mask, Hiro.
他沖進去是為了救你
He went in there to save you!
那是他自己太沖動了
That was his mistake!
白球恩  干掉他
Baymax, destroy.
我的程序設定不允許我傷害人類
My programing prevents me from injuring a human being.
不再是了
Not anymore.
宏  這不是...
Hiro, this is not what...
去吧  白球恩  干掉他
Do it, Baymax! Destroy him!
不  住手  白球恩
No! Stop, Baymax!
不  快放手  他要跑了
No, stop! He's getting away!
白球恩
Baymax!
我違反了程序設定的健康協議
My healthcare protocol has been violated.
很抱歉對你們造成了傷害
I regret any distress I may have caused.
你們怎么能這樣  我都抓住他了
How could you do that? I had him!
你剛剛做的事  我們可沒事先說好
What you just did, we never signed up for.
我們只說好抓住他
We said we'd catch the guy.
僅此而已
That's it.
我就不該讓你們幫我
I never should have let you help me!
白球恩  定位卡拉翰
Baymax, find Callaghan.
強化掃描儀故障了
My enhanced scanner has been damaged.
展開雙翼
Wings.
宏  這不是計劃的一部分
Hiro, this isn't part of the plan.
起飛
Fly!
宏
Hiro!
你的血壓升高了
Your blood pressure is elevated.
表明你正處于煩惱中
You appear to be distressed.
我沒事
I'm fine!
好了  能用了嗎
There. Is it working?
-傳感器工作正常  -很好
- My sensor is operational. - Good.
那就去
Then let's get...
搞什么
What?
你要移除我的醫療芯片嗎
Are you going to remove my healthcare chip?
是的  快打開
Yes. Open!
我的設計初衷是治愈疾病和傷痛
My purpose is to heal the sick and injured.
白球恩  打開你的芯片槽
Baymax, open your access port.
你要我終結卡拉翰教授嗎
Do you want me to terminate Professor Callaghan?
快打開它
Just open!
終結卡拉翰教授
Will terminating Professor Callaghan
就能平復你的情緒嗎
improve your emotional state?
沒錯  不  我不知道
Yes! No! I don't know!
快開啟芯片槽
Open your access!
-這是正想看到的嗎  -不重要
- Is this what Tadashi wanted? - It doesn't matter!
正的設計初衷旨在幫助他人并...
Tadashi programed me to aid and...
正死了
Tadashi's gone!
正已經不在了
Tadashi's gone.
正在這兒
Tadashi is here.
不  他已經不在了
No. He's not here.
正還在這兒
Tadashi is here.
我是濱田正
This is Tadashi Hamada.
這是我機器人項目的第一次測試
And this is the first test of my robotics project.
你好  我是白球恩
Hello, I am Baymax.
停下  停下  快停下
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
機器人項目第七次測試
The seventh test of my robotics project.
你好  我...
Hello, I...
搞什么
What? What?
等等  停下  停止掃描  停...
Wait, wait, wait, stop! Stop scan! Stop...
還是我  濱田正
Tadashi Hamada again,
這是我項目的第三十三次測試
and this is the 33rd test of my robotics project.
我不會放棄你的
I'm not giving up on you.
你可能還不明白  但是人們會需要你的
You don't understand this yet, but people need you.
咱們繼續努力吧
So, let's get back to work.
我是濱田正
This is Tadashi Hamada,
這是第八十四次測試
and this is the 84th test.
準備好了嗎  大家伙
What do you say, big guy?
你好  我是白球恩
Hello, I am Baymax,
你的個人醫療保健伙伴
your personal healthcare companion.
成功了
It works.
It works!
太棒了  竟然...成功了
This is amazing! You... you work!
我就知道能行
I knew it! I knew it! I knew it.
我就知道  會成功的  難以置信
I knew it. Oh, you work. I can't believe it! I can't...
好吧  最關鍵的一步
Okay. All right, big moment, here.
掃描我
Scan me.
你的神經傳遞素明顯增多
Your neurotransmitter levels are elevated.
表明你現在十分開心
This indicates that you are happy.
是的  超級開心
I am. I really am.
天啊  我得帶我弟來看看
Oh, man. Wait till my brother sees you.
你一定能幫助很多人  伙計
You're gonna help so many people, buddy.
很多很多人
So many.
先這樣吧  我很滿意你的服務
That's all for now. I am satisfied with my care.
謝謝你  白球恩
Thank you, Baymax.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我一點也趕不上我哥哥
I guess I'm not like my brother.
宏
Hiro.
伙計們  我...
Guys, I, I...
我們一起去阻止卡拉翰
We're going to catch Callaghan,
這次一定不會搞砸
and, this time, we'll do it right.
下次可別再把你的隊友
But maybe don't leave your team
丟在陰森森的島上了
stranded on a spooky island next time.
-抱歉  -沒關系
- Oh, man. - Nah, it's cool.
希斯克里夫開直升機把我們接來的
Heathcliff picked us up in the family chopper.
宏  你得看看這個
Hiro, we found something you should see.
你差點害死我們
You almost got us all killed!
克瑞  都怪你
Krei! You did this!
你早知道計劃還不完善
You knew it wasn't ready!
卡拉翰  他怎么也在
Callaghan? He was there?
他本是個好人啊  發生了什么
He was such a good man. What happened?
不知道
I don't know.
答案一定藏在某處
But the answer's here somewhere.
等等  暫停
Wait, wait! Stop.
他在那兒
There he is.
和飛行員一起
With the pilot.
等等
Hang on.
既然請來了這么多人...
We've invited all these people...
卡拉翰
飛行員是卡拉翰的女兒
The pilot was Callaghan's daughter.
所以卡拉翰才怪罪于克瑞
Callaghan blames Krei.
他要為女兒復仇
This is a revenge story.
還等什么
So, what are we waiting for?
都布置好了
It's all set up.
這美麗的新園區是我畢生夢想的至高點
This beautiful new campus is the culmination of a lifelong dream.
感謝人生路上遇到的絆腳石
But none of this would've been possible
不然我也不會站在這
without a few bumps in the road.
克瑞高科技工業園
這些障礙使我們變得更加強壯
Those setbacks made us stronger,
并引領我們走向光明的未來
and set us on the path to a bright future.
那是什么
What is that?
-什么  -障礙
- What? - Setback?
我女兒在你眼中只是"障礙"嗎
Was my daughter a "Setback"?
卡拉翰  你不是...
Callaghan! But you...
你女兒那是...
Your daughter, that...
那是個意外
That was an accident.
不  你明知那個實驗很危險
No! You knew it was unsafe.
我女兒就是因你的自大而喪生的
My daughter is gone because of your arrogance.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
你將艾比蓋爾送進機艙時
You took everything from me
便已奪走了我的一切
when you sent Abigail into that machine.
現在我要以牙還牙
Now I'm taking everything from you.
不
No!
不  不  別這樣
No! No! You can't!
你所有的成就將在你面前消失殆盡
You're going to watch everything you've built disappear.
然后就輪到你
Then, it's your turn.
卡拉翰教授
Professor Callaghan!
放開他
Let him go!
這是艾比蓋爾希望看到的嗎
Is this what Abigail would've wanted?
艾比蓋爾已經不在了
Abigail is gone!
這么做于事無補  相信我  我也經歷過
This won't change anything. Trust me, I know.
這孩子說得沒錯  卡拉翰
Listen to the kid, Callaghan.
求你放了我吧
Please, let me go.
你要什么我都給你
I'll give you anything you want!
我要我女兒回來
I want my daughter back!
擊落他的面具
Go for the mask!
白球恩
Baymax!
作戰開始
Leaping into action!
不好
Oh, no!
這下壓力有點大
Getting a little... A little tight.
-不妙  -他太強大了
- No! - He's too strong!
-我出不去了  -根本贏不了
- There's no way out! - You can't beat him!
救命  我斗不過他
Help! I can't beat him.
宏
Hiro!
-宏  宏  -救命
- Hiro? Hiro? - Help!
-對了  -宏
- That's it! - Hiro.
-我知道怎么戰勝他了  -宏
- I know how to beat him. - Hiro.
聽好了
Listen up!
動動你們的腦子
Use those big brains of yours,
把思路打開
and think your way around the problem.
換個新角度
Look for a new angle.
我的胳膊  再扯就斷了
My arms! They can't go any further!
等一下  這是個外套
Wait a second, it's a suit.
你好啊  鐵片
Hello, sign.
介意讓我轉一下嗎
Care to go for a little spin?
二連轉
Double spin!
背轉式
Behind-the-back spin!
白球恩
Baymax!
宏
Hiro.
我愛死那個機器人了
I love that robot!
好了  新計劃  別管面具了
Okay, new plan. Forget the mask.
先對付微型機器人  把它們弄進傳送門
Take out the bots. They'll get sucked up into the portal.
這才叫計劃
Now that is a plan!
小蜜  弗雷迪  能作掩護嗎
Honey, Fred, can you give us some cover?
還用你說
Like you have to ask.
行動吧  弗雷迪
Let's do this, Freddie!
煙幕彈
Smokescreen!
預備
Ready and
俯沖
dive!
這邊的重力有點異常  伙計們
Whoa, the gravity's getting a little weird here, guys!
正好將計就計
Wait. Let's use this!
嘗嘗充滿怒火的綠刃吧
These are green blades of fury!
女人雄起
Woman up!
雙牌花式
Double sign-spin.
老子的鐵片熱力四射
Now my signs are on fire!
這才叫化學反應
Now that's a chemical reaction!
后踢  手刀  回旋踢
Back kick. Knifehand. Roundhouse.
劈拳
Hammerfist.
你們完了
This ends now!
看來微型機器人不夠用了
Looks like you're out of microbots.
什么
What?
白球恩
Baymax!
不
No!
程序設定不允許我們傷害人類
Our programing prevents us from injuring a human being.
不過這個歸我們了
But we'll take that.
它仍在運行  我們得關閉它
It's still on! We have to shut it down!
辦不到  遏制場正在失效
We can't! The containment field is failing.
傳送門會自己銷毀
The portal is gonna tear itself apart!
我們必須馬上離開這兒
We need to get out of here, now!
白球恩
Baymax!
傳感器檢測到了生命跡象
My sensor is detecting signs of life.
-什么  -從那里面傳出來的
- What? - Coming from there.
是女性的生命體征
The life signs are female.
她正處于深度休眠中
She appears to be in hyper-sleep.
是卡拉翰的女兒  她還活著
Callaghan's daughter. She's still alive.
艾比蓋爾
Abigail.
我們去接她回來
Let's go get her.
傳送門正在解體  你們做不到的
The portal is destabilizing. You'll never make it.
她還活著
She's alive in there.
總得有人去救她
Someone has to help.
你說呢  伙計
What do you say, buddy?
飛行確實讓我成為更稱職的醫療保健伙伴
Flying makes me a better healthcare companion.
小心  這里到處都是碎片
Careful! There's Krei tech debris everywhere.
小心
Look out!
已定位到患者
I have located the patient.
快去
Hurry!
來吧  伙計  帶她回家
Come on, buddy, let's get her home.
我來指路  出發
I'll guide you out of here. Let's go!
右轉
Veer right!
好的  朝左飛
Okay, to the left.
右急轉彎
Hard right!
向上穿過去
Up and over.
好的  穩定向前  穩一點
Okay, level off. Easy.
飛得好
Nice flying!
就快到了
Almost there!
白球恩
Baymax!
推進器失靈了
My thrusters are inoperable.
抓住我的手
Just grab hold.
還有一種辦法能讓你們安全逃生
There is still a way I can get you both to safety.
在你沒對我的服務表示滿意之前
I cannot deactivate until you say
我無法進入休眠
you are satisfied with your care.
不  不  不  等等  你怎么辦
No, no, no, no. Wait. What about you?
-你是我的患者  -白球恩
- You are my patient. - Baymax.
我只在乎你的安危
Your health is my only concern.
別說了  我會想出辦法
Stop! I'm gonna figure out...
你對我的服務滿意嗎
Are you satisfied with your care?
不  肯定還有別的辦法的
No. There's gotta be another way.
我不會把你丟下的  我會想出辦法來的
I'm not gonna leave you here. I'll think of something.
沒時間了
There is no time.
你對我的服務滿意嗎
Are you satisfied with your care?
求你了  別走
Please! No.
我不能再失去你
I can't lose you, too.
宏  我會一直陪在你身邊
Hiro, I will always be with you.
我很滿意你的服務
I'm satisfied with my care.
宏
Hiro!
太好了  他們成功了
Yeah! They made it!
白球恩呢
Baymax?
小姐  能聽見嗎
Miss, can you hear me?
你還記得自己的名字嗎
What is your name?
艾比蓋爾·卡拉翰
Abigail Callaghan.
好的  艾比蓋爾  你會沒事的
Okay, Abigail, you are gonna be fine.
我們這就送你去醫院
We're taking you to the hospital.
過來
Move it!
進去
Get in there.
今天克瑞科技工業的總部
A massive cleanup continues today
仍在進行大量的清理工作
at the headquarters of Krei Tech Industries.
機器人學教授羅伯特·卡拉翰由于涉嫌摧毀克瑞科技園區而被拘留
有關神秘團體
Reports are still flooding in
阻止災難發生的報導
about a group of unidentified individuals,
也如潮水般發布開來
who prevented what could have been a major catastrophe.
整個舊京山都在疑惑
The whole city of San Fransokyo is asking,
"這些英雄到底是誰  他們現在在何處"
"Who are these heroes? And where are they now?"
真是激動人心
It's so exciting.
親愛的
Hey, sweetie!
好了
Okay.
再抱一下
Last hug.
再見
Bye!
-然后我就像...-一邊兒去
- And just then I was like... - Get out of here.
我是白球恩  你的個人醫療保健伙伴
I am Baymax, your personal healthcare companion.
你好  宏
Hello, Hiro.
我們并非天生就是超級英雄
We didn't set out to be superheroes,
但生活不總會按照計劃進行
but sometimes life doesn't go the way you planned.
好消息是  我哥哥希望能幫助更多的人
The good thing is, my brother wanted to help a lot of people,
這也是我們所要做的
and that's what we're gonna do.
我們是誰
Who are we?
超能
陸戰隊
片尾有彩蛋
老爸  真希望能和你分享我的成就
Dad, I just wish I could share my accomplishments with you.
你對我真的很重要  而且老實說
You mean so much to me, and honestly,
你總待在那個島上
I've always felt a distance
咱倆之間都有隔閡了
what with you being on the family island all the time,
我只希望你能看看...
and I just wish you could see how...
弗雷迪
Fred.
兒子
Son.
老爸
Dad?
正面穿完反面穿
I wear 'em front, I wear 'em back.
臟了翻面還能穿
I go inside out, then I go front and back.
老爸
Dad!
看來咱爺倆有得聊了
We have a lot to talk about.